canon.com.au 2013-06-04

# Privacy Policy - Canon Australia

### Introduction

This is the Privacy Policy of Canon Australia Pty Limited (ABN 66 005 002 951) and its wholly-owned subsidiary, Canon Finance Australia Pty Limited (ABN 21 003 637 116) (“ **CFA** ”), (collectively, “ **Canon** ”). Its purpose is to inform individuals of our policies and practices regarding the collection, use, disclosure and storage of their personal information.  

### General

Canon respects individuals’ privacy. Canon is bound by, and complies with, the National Privacy Principles (“ **NPPs** ”) prescribed under the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth). (Further information regarding the NPPs can be found at the Privacy Commissioner’s website at [www.privacy.gov.au](http://www.privacy.gov.au/))

Canon also complies with the credit reporting provisions contained in Part IIIA of the Privacy Act, insofar as they apply to Canon in connection with the provision of commercial credit.  

### Collection of personal information

In accordance with NPP1:

  * Canon will not collect personal information unless the information is necessary for one or more of its functions or activities. 
  * Canon will only collect personal information by lawful and fair means and not in an unreasonably intrusive way. 
  * When or before collecting personal information, Canon will take all reasonable steps (via this Policy and otherwise) to ensure the individual is aware of the required matters (and, where necessary in the case of sensitive information, has given his/her consent to the collection). 
  * Whenever it is reasonable and practicable to do so, Canon will only collect personal information about an individual from that individual, and otherwise will take reasonable steps to ensure that the individual is made aware of the required matters.

###   
Use and disclosure of personal information

In accordance with NPP2:

  * Canon may use and/or disclose personal information for the primary purpose for which it was collected. Such primary purposes may include: 
    * to administer and improve the performance of Canon-owned websites; 
    * to deliver goods and services; 
    * to address and respond to concerns or other correspondence from customers; 
    * to deliver benefits and services to MyCanon members; 
    * to assess applications for commercial credit and potential guarantors; and 
    * to administer and enforce commercial credit and guarantee agreements. 
  * Subject to any contrary legal obligations, Canon will only use and/or disclose personal information for secondary purposes where NPP2 permits, which includes: 
    * where the secondary purpose is related to the primary purpose of collection, and the individual would reasonably expect such other use or disclosure; or 
    * where the individual consents. 
  * Organisations to which Canon typically may disclose personal information collected by it are companies within its corporate group, and service providers (such as credit card processors, providers of outsourced services, shipping agents, advertising and marketing agencies, and credit reporting agencies), but only to the extent necessary to enable those other entities to assist Canon in fulfilling the primary purposes for which Canon collected the information, and any permitted secondary purposes. All such entities are required to keep such information confidential and restrict their use of it to the permitted purposes. 
  * Canon will never sell or rent personal information collected by it to third parties for marketing purposes.

###   
Collection, use and disclosure – specific situations

Browsing Canon-owned websites:

  * Canon may collect information about individuals’ visits to Canon-owned websites using automatic collection tools, such as “cookies”. We do this in order to monitor traffic patterns and serve individuals more efficiently if they revisit the sites. Such tools do not identify individuals personally, but they can provide information such as the individuals’ browser type and language, access times, Internet Protocol addresses and behaviour (e.g. pages visited, links clicked).

MyCanon:

  * Individuals need to become members of MyCanon if they wish to access a number of extra benefits and services from Canon-owned websites, which may include: 
    * the ability to enter and participate in Canon competitions and promotions online; 
    * the ability to register their Canon products for warranty purposes; 
    * the opportunity to subscribe to various communications, including newsletters and special offers; 
    * the opportunity to submit Ratings and Reviews; and 
    * the opportunity to contribute to online discussions. 
  * When joining MyCanon, individuals are asked to provide such personal information as is needed to enable Canon to supply the extra benefits or services desired by those individuals, as indicated by the options to which they subscribe (which will be presented to them in the course of the MyCanon registration process). Canon will only use or disclose that personal information for the purposes of supplying those benefits or services. 
  * Members of MyCanon can alter their preferences at any time, including by unsubscribing from any email or SMS communications. Canon complies with the Spam Act 2003 (Cth) in relation to any such communications or other electronic messages. 
  * In addition to the information individuals provide when joining MyCanon, Canon may also collect, and aggregate such information with: 
    * information which those individuals subsequently voluntarily contribute to us and/or Canon-owned websites; 
    * information obtained from the automatic collection tools referred to above.

###   
Data quality

In accordance with NPP3, Canon will take all reasonable steps to ensure that the personal information it collects, uses or discloses is accurate, complete and up-to-date.

###   
Data security

In accordance with NPP4:

  * Canon will take all reasonable steps to protect the personal information it holds from misuse and loss and from unauthorised access, modification or disclosure. 
  * Canon will take all reasonable steps to destroy or permanently de-identify personal information if it is no longer needed for any purpose for which the information may be used or disclosed under NPP2.

###   
Openness

In accordance with NPP5:

  * On request by a person, Canon will take all reasonable steps to let the person know, generally, what sort of personal information it holds, for what purposes, and how it collects, holds, uses and discloses that information.

###   
Access and correction

In accordance with NPP6:

  * Canon will give an individual access to any personal information which it holds about that individual, subject to the limited exceptions set out in NPP6. 
  * If an individual establishes that personal information which Canon holds about him/her is not accurate, complete and up-to-date, Canon will take all reasonable steps to correct the information.

###   
Children

Children (persons under the age of 18 years) are eligible to access and use the Site. However, if you are under the age of 15 we request that you obtain the consent of your parent/s or guardian/s before submitting any personal information to the Site.

###   
Changes to this Policy

Canon reserves the right to change this Policy from time to time, in accordance with relevant circumstances. If we do so, we will post the revised Policy here. We may also give notice by other means, such as a message on our website.

###   
How to contact us

Any complaints, problems or queries regarding Canon’s management of personal information should be directed to Canon’s Privacy Officer by:

  * phoning (02) 9805 2000; or 
  * sending an email to: [privacyofficer@canon.com.au](mailto:privacyofficer@canon.com.au)
